<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on Aravind&#39;s Blog | R | Economics | Finance</title>
    <link>/tags/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on Aravind&#39;s Blog | R | Economics | Finance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Line Graphs</title>
      <link>/2017/04/19/ggplot2-line-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/19/ggplot2-line-graphs/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the 8th post in the series Elegant Data Visualization with ggplot2. In the previous post, we learnt to build scatter plots. In this post, we will learn to
buildsimple line chartgrouped line chartmap aesthetics to variablesmodify linecolortypesizeLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataWe will use the following libraries in this post:
readrggplot2All the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Scatter Plots</title>
      <link>/2017/04/04/ggplot2-scatter-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/04/ggplot2-scatter-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the fifth post in the series Elegant Data Visualization with ggplot2. In the previous post, we learnt about text annotations. In this post, we will build scatter plots by applying everything we have learnt so far.
build scatter plotsmodify pointcolorfillalphashapesizefit regression lineLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataWe will use the following libraries in this post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Text Annotations</title>
      <link>/2017/03/17/ggplot2-text-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/17/ggplot2-text-annotations/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the sixth post in the series Elegant Data Visualization with ggplot2. In the previous post, we learnt to modify the axis and plot labels. In this post, we will learn to add text to the plots.
add custom textmodify colormodify sizemodify fontfacemodify angleLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataWe will use the following libraries in this post:
readrggplot2All the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Introduction to aesthetics</title>
      <link>/2017/02/24/ggplot2-introduction-to-aesthetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/24/ggplot2-introduction-to-aesthetics/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the fourth post in the series Elegant Data Visualization with ggplot2. In the previous post we learnt about geoms and how we can use them to build different plots. In this post, we will focus on the aesthetics i.e. color, shape, size, alpha, line type, line width etc. We can map these to variables or specify values for them. If we want to map the above to variables, we have to specify them within the aes() function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Introduction to geoms</title>
      <link>/2017/02/11/ggplot2-introduction-to-geoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/11/ggplot2-introduction-to-geoms/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the third post in the series Elegant Data Visualization with ggplot2. In the previous post, we learnt how to create plots using the qplot() function. In this post, we will create some of the most routinely used plots to explore data using the geom_* functions.
Libraries, Code &amp;amp; DataWe will use the following libraries in this post:
readrggplot2tibbledplyrAll the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2: Quick Tour</title>
      <link>/2017/01/22/ggplot2-quick-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/22/ggplot2-quick-tour/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the second post in the series Elegant Data Visualization with ggplot2. In the previous post, we understood the concept of grammar of graphics and even built a bar plot step by step while exploring the different components of a plot/chart. In this post, we willlearn to quickly build a set of plots that are routinely used to explore data.
Libraries, Code &amp;amp; DataWe will use the following libraries in this post:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with R - Combining Plots</title>
      <link>/2016/12/17/data-visualization-with-r-combining-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/17/data-visualization-with-r-combining-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the tenth post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we learnt how to add text annotations to plots. In this post, we will learn how to combine multiple plots. Often, it is useful to have multiple plots in the same frame as it allows us to get a comprehensive view of a particular variable or compare among different variables. The Graphics package offers two methods to combine multiple plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with R - Text Annotations</title>
      <link>/2016/12/08/data-visualization-with-r-text-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/08/data-visualization-with-r-text-annotations/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the ninth post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we learnt how to add legend to a plot. In this post, we will learn to add text annotations. There are occassions when you want to display additional information in a plot. This is usually achieved by adding text either inside the plot or on the margins. For example, you might want to label a line/bar or add formulas to better communicate what is shown in the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with R - Legends</title>
      <link>/2016/11/25/data-visualization-with-r-legends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/25/data-visualization-with-r-legends/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the eighth post in the series Data Visualisation With R. In the previous post, we learnt to build histograms. In this post, we will learn how to:
position the legend within the plotmodify the layout using ncol and horiz argumentsadd title using the title. set of argumentsmodify the appearance and position of the legend boxmodify the appearance of the text in the legend boxLegends are used to convey information about the data being represented by a plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with R - Histogram</title>
      <link>/2016/11/06/data-visualization-with-r-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/11/06/data-visualization-with-r-histogram/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the seventh post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we learnt about box and whisker plots. In this post, we will learn to:
create a bare bones histogramspecify the number of bins/intervalsrepresent frequency density on the Y axisadd colors to the bars and the borderadd labels to the barsA histogram is a plot that can be used to examine the shape and spread of continuous data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with R - Box Plots</title>
      <link>/2016/10/21/data-visualization-with-r-box-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/21/data-visualization-with-r-box-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the sixth post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we learnt how to build bar plots. In this post, we will learn to
create univariate/multivariate box plotsinterpret box plotscreate horizontal box plotsdetect outliersmodify box coloruse formula to compare distributions of different variablesuse notches to compare mediansLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataAll the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization With R - Bar Plots</title>
      <link>/2016/10/05/data-visualization-with-r-bar-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/05/data-visualization-with-r-bar-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the fifth post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post we learnt how to build line graphs. In this post, we will visualize categorical data using univariate and bivariate bar plots.
createsimple bar plotstacked bar plotgrouped bar plotmodify bardirectioncolorline colorwidthlabelsmodify axis rangeremove axes from the plotspecify the line type of the X axesoffset the Y axesmodify legendLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataAll the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization With R - Line Graphs</title>
      <link>/2016/09/23/data-visualization-with-r-line-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/23/data-visualization-with-r-line-graphs/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the fourth post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we learnt how to build scatter plots. In this post, we will build line graphs. To be more specific we will learn to
create line plotsadd color to linesmodify line type/stylemodify line widthadd points to the linesmodify axis rangeadd additional lines to the plotLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataAll the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization With R - Scatter Plots</title>
      <link>/2016/09/07/data-visualization-with-r-scatter-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/07/data-visualization-with-r-scatter-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the third post in the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we learned how to add title, subtitle and axis labels. We also learned how to modify the range of the axis. In this post, we will learn how to create scatter plots. If you remember, we had created a scatter plot in this post, using the plot() function. We will continue with the same plot and learn how to enhance a scatter plot by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization With R - Title and Axis Labels</title>
      <link>/2016/08/22/data-visualization-with-r-title-and-axis-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/22/data-visualization-with-r-title-and-axis-labels/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the second post of the series Data Visualization With R. In the previous post, we explored the plot() function and observed the different types of plots it generated. In this post, we will learn how to add:
TitleSubtitleAxis Labelsto a plot and how to modify:
Axis rangeIn the previous post, we created plots which did not have any title or labels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization With R - Introduction</title>
      <link>/2016/08/05/data-visualization-with-r-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/05/data-visualization-with-r-introduction/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis is the first post of the series Data Visualization With R. The objective of the series is to provide a gentle introduction to working with base graphics in R. We will come up with a similar series using ggplot2 shortly.
what is data visualizationwhy visualize dataunderstand R graphics systemgraphicsggplot2latticebuild some simple plotsLibraries, Code &amp;amp; DataAll the data sets used in this post can be found here and code can be downloaded from here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>